Flies. Chapter 5. Beast from Water. The tide was coming in, and there was only a
narrow strip of firm beach between the water and the white, stumbling stuff
near the palm Terrace. Ralph chose the firm strip as a path because he needed
to think, and only here could he allow his feet to move without having to watch
them. Suddenly, pacing by the water, he was overcome with astonishment. He found
himself understanding the wearomeness of this life where every path was an
improvisation and a considerable part of one's waking life was spent watching
one's feet. He stopped facing the strip and remembering that first enthusiastic
exploration as though it were part of a brighter childhood. He smiled
jeeringly. He turned then and walked back toward the platform with the sun in
his face. The time had come for the assembly, and as he walked into the
concealing splenders of the sunlight, he went carefully over the points of his
speech. There must be no mistake about this assembly. No chasing imaginary. He
lost himself in a maze of thoughts that were rendered vague by his lack of words
to express them. Frowning he tried again. This meeting must not be fun but
business. At that he walked faster, aware all at once of urgency in the
declining sun and a little wind created by his speed that breathed about his
face. This wind pressed his gray shirt against his chest so that he noticed in
this new mood of comprehension how the folds were stiff like cardboard and
unpleasant. Notice too how the frayed edges of his shorts were making an
uncomfortable pink area on the front of his thighs. With a convulsion of the
mind, Ralph discovered dirt and decay, understood how much he disliked
perpetually flicking the tangled hair out of his eyes, and at last, when the
sun was gone, rolling noisily to rest among dry leaves. At that, he began to
trot. The beach near the bathing pool was dotted with groups of boys waiting
for the assembly. They made way for him silently, conscious of his grim mood and
the fault of the fire. The place of assembly in which he stood was roughly a
triangle, but irregular and sketchy like everything they made. First there was
the log on which he himself sat, a dead tree that must have been quite
exceptionally big for the platform.
Perhaps one of those legendary storms of the Pacific had shifted it here. His
palm trunk lay parallel to the beach, so that when Ralph sat he faced the island,
but to the boys was a darkish figure against the shimmer of the lagoon. The
two sides of the triangle of which the log was based were less evenly defined.
On the right was a log polished by restless seats along the top, but not so
large as the chiefs and not so comfortable. On the left were four small
logs, one of them the farthest, lamentably springy. Assembly after
assembly had broken up in laughter when someone had leaned too far back, and the
log had whipped and thrown half a dozen boys backwards into the grass. Yet now
he saw, no one had had the wit, not himself, nor Jack, nor Piggy, to bring a
stone and wedge the thing. So they would continue enduring the illbalanced
twister because because again he lost himself in deep waters. Grass was worn
away in front of each trunk but grew tall and untrodden in the center of the
triangle. Then at the apex the grass was thick again because no one sat there.
All around the place of assembly the gray trunks rose straight or leaning and
supported the low roof of leaves. On two sides was the beach behind the lagoon in
front the darkness of the island. Ralph turned to the chief's seat. They had
never had an assembly as late before.
That was why the place looked so different. Normally, the underside of
the green roof was lit by a tangle of golden reflections, and their faces were
lit upside down, like thought Ralph when you hold an electric torch in your
hands. But now the sun was slanting in at one side, so that the shadows were
where they ought to be. Again, he fell into that strange mood of speculation
that was so foreign to him. If faces were different when lit from above or
below, what was a face? What was anything? Ralph moved impatiently. The
trouble was, if you were a chief, you had to think. You had to be wise and
then the occasion slipped by so that you had to grab at a decision. This made you
think because thought was a valuable thing that got results. Only decided
Ralph as he faced the chief's seat. I can't think, not like Piggy. Once more
that evening, Ralph had to adjust his values. Piggy could think. He could go
step by step inside that fat head of his. Only Piggy was no chief. But Piggy,
for all his ludicrous body, had brains.
Ralph was a specialist in thought now and could recognize thought in another.
The sun in his eyes reminded him how time was passing, so he took the conchk
down from the tree and examined the surface. Exposure to the air had
bleached the yellow and pink to near white and transparency. Ralph felt a kind of
affectionate reverence for the conchk, even though he had fished the thing out
of the lagoon himself. He faced the place of assembly and put the conchk to
his lips. The others were waiting for this and came straight away. Those who
were aware that a ship had passed the island while the fire was out were
subdued by the thought of Ralph's anger, while those, including the little who
did not know, were impressed by the general air of somnity. The place of
assembly filled quickly. Jack, Simon, Maurice, most of the hunters on Ralph's
right, the rest on the left under the sun. Piggy came and stood outside the
triangle. This indicated that he wished to listen but would not speak, and Piggy
intended it as a gesture of disapproval.
The thing is, we need an assembly. No one said anything, but the faces turned
to Ralph were intent. He flourished the conchk. He had learned as a practical
business that fundamental statements like this had to be said at least twice
before everyone understood them. One had to sit, attracting all eyes to the
conchk, and drop words like heavy round stones among the little groups that
crouched or squatted. He was searching his mind for simple words so that even
the little ends would understand what the assembly was about. Later perhaps,
practice debaters, Jack, Maurice, Piggy, would use their whole art to twist the
meeting. But now, at the beginning, the subject of the debate must be laid out
clearly. We need an assembly, not for fun, not for laughing and falling off
the log. The group of little ends on the twister giggled and looked at each
other. Not for making jokes, or for He lifted the conchk in an effort to find the compelling
word. For cleverness, not for these things, but to put things straight. He
paused for a moment. I've been alone by myself. I went thinking what's what. I
know what we need. An assembly to put things straight and first of all I'm
speaking. He paused for a moment and automatically pushed back his hair.
Piggy tiptoed to the triangle his ineffectual protest made and joined the
others. Ralph went on. We have lots of assemblies. Everybody enjoys speaking
and being together. We decide things, but they don't get done. We were going
to have water brought from the stream and left in those coconut shells under
fresh leaves. So it was for a few days.
Now there's no water. The shells are dry. People drink from the river. There
was a murmur of a scent. Not that there's anything wrong with drinking
from the river. I mean, I'd sooner have water from that place, you know, the
pool where the waterfall is, than out of an old coconut shell. Only we said we'd
have the water brought, and now not.
There were only two full shells there this afternoon. He licked his lips. Then
there's huts, shelters. The murmur swelled again and died away. You mostly
sleep in shelters. Tonight, except for Sam and Eric up by the fire, you'll all
sleep there. Who built the shelters?
Clamor rose at once. Everyone had built the shelters. Ralph had to wave the
conchk once more. Wait a minute. I mean, who built all three? We all built the
first one. Four of us the second one, and me and Simon built the last one over
there. That's why it's so toty. No, don't laugh. That shelter might fall
down if the rain comes back. We'll need those shelters then. He paused and
cleared his throat. There's another thing. We chose those rocks right along
beyond the bathing pool as a lavatory.
That was sensible, too. The tide cleansed the place up. You little know
about that. There were sniggers here and there and swift glances. Now people seem
to use anywhere, even near the shelters and the platform. You little when you're
getting fruit, if you're taken short, the assembly roared. I said if you're
taken short, you keep away from the fruit. That's dirty. Laughter rose
again. I said that's dirty. He plucked at his stiff gray shirt. That's really
dirty. If you're taken short, you go right along the beach to the rocks. See?
Piggy held out his hands for the conchk, but Ralph shook his head. His speech was
planned point by point. We've all got to use the rocks again. This place is
getting dirty. He paused. The assembly, sensing a crisis, was tensely expectant.
And then about the fire. Ralph let out his spare breath with a little gasp that
was echoed by his audience. Jack started to chip a piece of wood with his knife
and whispered something to Robert, who looked away. The fire is the most
important thing on the island. How can we ever be rescued except by luck if we
don't keep a fire going? Is a fire too much for us to make? He flung out an
arm. Look at us. How many are we? And yet we can't keep a fire going to make
smoke. Don't you understand? Can't you see we ought to ought to die before we
let the fire out? There was a self-conscious giggling among the hunters. Ralph turned on them
passionately. You hunters, you can laugh. But I tell you, the smoke is more
important than the pig, however often you kill one. Do all of you see? He
spread his arms wide and turned to the whole triangle. We've got to make smoke
up there or die. He paused, feeling for his next point. And another thing,
someone called out. Too many things.
There came a mutter of agreement. Ralph overrode them. And another thing. We
nearly set the whole island on fire, and we waste time rolling rocks and making
little cooking fires. Now, I say this and make it a rule because I'm chief. We
won't have a fire anywhere but on the mountain ever. There was a row
immediately. Boys stood up and shouted, and Ralph shouted back, "Because if you
want a fire to cook fish or crab, you can jolly well go up the mountain. That
way, we'll be certain." Hands were reaching for the conchk. in the light of
the setting sun. He held on and leapt on the trunk. All this I meant to say, now
I've said it. You voted me for chief, now you do what I say. They quieted
slowly and at last proceeded again.
Ralph dropped down and spoke in his ordinary voice. So remember, the rocks
were a lavatory. Keep the fire going and smoke showing as a signal. Don't take
fire from the mountain. Take your food up there. Jack stood up, scowlling in
the gloom, and held out his hands. I haven't finished yet. But you've talked
and talked. I've got the conchk. Jack sat down, grumbling. Then the last
thing, this is what people can talk about. He waited till the platform was very
still. Things are breaking up. I don't understand why. We began well. We were
happy. And then he moved the conchk gently, looking beyond them at nothing,
remembering the beasty, the snake, the fire, the talk of fear. Then people
started getting frightened. A murmur, almost a moan, rose and passed away.
Jack had stopped whittling. Ralph went on abruptly. But that's Little's talk.
We'll get that straight. So, the last part, the bit we can all talk about, is
kind of deciding on the fear. The hair was creeping into his eyes again. We've
got to talk about this fear and decide there's nothing in it. I'm frightened
myself sometimes, only that's nonsense, like bogeies. Then, when we've decided,
we can start again and be careful about things like the fire. A picture of three
boys walking along the bright beach flitted through his mind. And be happy.
Ceremonially, Ralph laid the conchk on the trunk beside him as a sign that the
beach was over. Once what sunlight reached them was level. Jack stood up
and took the So this is a meeting to find out what's what. I'll tell you
what's what. You little started all this with the fear talk. Beasts where from?
Of course we're frightened sometimes, but we put up with being frightened.
Only Ralph says you scream in the night.
What does that mean but nightmares? Anyway, you don't hunt or
build or help. You're a lot of cryb babies and sissies. That's what. And as
for the fear, you'll have to put up with that like the rest of us. Ralph looked
at Jack openmouthed, but Jack took no notice. The thing is, fear can't hurt
you any more than a dream. There aren't any beasts to be afraid of on this
island. He looked along the row of whispering little ones. Sir, you right
if something did get you, you useless lot of cryb babies. But there is no
animal. Ralph interrupted him testily.
What is all this? Who said anything about an animal? You did the other day.
You said they dream and cry out. Now they talk, not only the little ones, but
my hunters sometimes talk of a thing, a dark thing, a beast, some sort of
animal. I've heard. You thought not, didn't you? Now listen. You don't get
big animals on small islands, only pigs.
You only get lions and tigers in big countries like Africa and India and the
zoo. I've got the conchk. I'm not talking about the fear. I'm talking
about the beast. Be frightened if you like. But as for the beast, Jack paused,
cradling the conchk and turned to his hunters with their dirty black caps. Am
I a hunter or am I not? They nodded simply. He was a hunter. All right. No
one doubted that. Well then, I've been all over this island by myself. If there
were a beast, I'd have seen it. be frightened because you're like that, but
there is no beast in the forest. Jack handed back the conchk and sat down. The
whole assembly applauded him with relief. Then Piggy held out his hand. I
don't agree with all, Jack said, but with some of there isn't a beast in the
forest. How could there be? What would a beast eat? Pig? We pig? Piggy? I got the
conchk, said Piggy indignantly. Ralph, they ought to shut up, oughtn't they?
You shut up, you little What I mean is that I don't agree about this here fear.
Of course, there isn't nothing to be afraid of in the forest. Why, I've been there myself.
You'll be talking about ghosts and such things next. We know what goes on, and
if there's something wrong, there's someone to put it right. He took off his
glasses and blinked at them. The sun had gone as if the light had been turned
off. He proceeded to explain. If you get a pain in your stomach, whether it's a
little one or a big one, yours is a big one. When you're done laughing, perhaps
we can get on with the meeting. And if them little ones climb back on the
twister again, they'll only fall off in a sec. So they might as well sit on the
ground and listen. No, you have doctors for everything, even the inside of your
mind. You don't really mean that we got to be frightened all the time of
nothing. Life, said S Piggy expansively, is scientific. That's what it is. In a
year or two, when the war is over, they'll be traveling to Mars and back. I
know there isn't no beast. Not with claws and all that. I mean, but I know
there isn't no fear either. Piggy paused. Unless, Ralph moved restlessly.
Unless what? Unless we get frightened of people. A sound, half laugh, half jer,
rose among the seated boys. Piggy ducked his head and went on hastily. So, let's
hear from that little who talked about a beast, and perhaps we can show him how
silly he is. The little onins began to jabber among themselves. Then one stood
forward. What's your name, Phil? For a little, he was self-confident, holding
out his hands, cradling the conchk as Ralph did, looking round at them to
collect their attention before he spoke.
Last night, I had a dream, a horrid dream, fighting with things. I was
outside the shelter by myself fighting with things, those twisty things in the
trees. He paused and the other little laughed in horrified sympathy. Then I
was frightened and I woke up and I was outside the shelter by myself in the
dark and the twisty things had gone away. The vivid horror of this so
possible and so nakedly terrifying held them all silent. The child's voice went
piping on from behind the white conchk, and I was frightened and started to call
out for Ralph. And then I saw something moving among the trees, something big
and horrid. He paused, half frightened by the recollection, yet proud of the
sensation he was creating. "That was a nightmare," said Ralph. "He was walking
in his sleep." The assembly murmured in subdued agreement. The little shook his
head stubbornly. "I was asleep when the twisty things were fighting, and when
they went away, I was awake, and I saw something big and horrid moving in the
trees." Ralph held out his hands for the conchk, and the little sat down. "You
were asleep. There wasn't anyone there.
How could anyone be wandering about in the forest at night? Was anyone? Did
anyone go out?" There was a long pause while the assembly grinned at the
thought of anyone going out in the darkness. Then Simon stood up and Ralph
looked at him in astonishment. You? What were you mcking about in the dark for?
Simon grabbed the conchk compulsively. I wanted to go to a place. A place I know.
What place? Just a place I know. A place in the jungle. He hesitated. Jack
settled the question for them with that contempt in his voice that could sound
so funny and so final. He was taken short. With a feeling of humiliation on
Simon's behalf, Ralph took back the conchk, looking Simon sternly in the
face as he did so. Well, don't do it again. Understand? Not at night. There's
enough silly talk about beasts without the little in seeing you gliding about
like a the derisive laughter that rose had fear in it and condemnation. Simon
opened his mouth to speak, but Ralph had the conchk, so he backed to his seat.
When the assembly was silent, Ralph turned to Piggy. Well, Piggy, there was
another one. Him. The little ones pushed Percible forward, then left him by
himself. He stood knee deep in the central grass, looking at his hidden
feet, trying to pretend he was in a tent. Ralph remembered another small boy
who had stood like this, and he flinched away from the memory. He had pushed the
thought down and out of sight, where only some positive reminder like this
could bring it to the surface. There had been no further numberings of the little
onins, partly because there was no means of ensuring that all of them were
accounted for, and partly because Ralph knew the answer to at least one question
Piggy had asked on the mountaintop.
There were little boys, fair, dark, freckled, and all dirty, but their faces
were all dreadfully free of major blemishes. No one had seen the malberry
colored birthark again. But that time, Piggy had coaxed and bullied, tacitly,
admitting that he remembered the unmentionable. Ralph nodded to Piggy. Go
on, ask him. Piggy knelt, holding the conchk. Now then, what's your name? The
small boy twisted away into his tent.
Piggy turned helplessly to Ralph who spoke sharply. What's your name?
Tormented by the silence and the refusal, the assembly broke into a
chant. What's your name? What's your name? Quiet. Ralph peered at the child
in the twilight. Now tell us, what's your name? Per Weis Madison, the
vicorage. Harkertson Anthony Hance.
Telephone. Telephone. Tele. As if this information was rooted far down in the
springs of sorrow. The little wept. His face puckered. The tears leapt from his
eyes. His mouth opened till they could see a square black hole. At first he was
a silent effigy of sorrow, but then the lamentation rose out of him loud and
sustained as the conchk. Shut up. You shut up. Perival Weis Madison would not
shut up. A spring had been tapped far beyond the reach of authority or even
physical intimidation. The crying went on breath after breath and seemed to
sustain him upright as if he were nailed to it. Shut up. Shut up. For now the
little were no longer silent. They were reminded of their personal sorrows and
perhaps felt themselves to share in a sorrow that was universal. They began to
cry in sympathy. Two of them almost as loud as Percal. Maurice saved them. He
cried out, "Look at me." He pretended to fall over. He rubbed his rump and sat on
the twister so that he fell in the grass. He clowned badly, but Pers and
the others noticed and sniffed and laughed. Presently they were all
laughing so absurdly that the biggin joined in. Jack was the first to make
himself heard. He had not got the conchk and thus spoke against the rules, but
nobody minded. "And what about the beast?" Something strange was happening
to Perl. He yawned and staggered so that Jack seized and shook him. "Where does
the beast live?" Percal sagged in Jack's grip.
That's a clever beast, said Piggy, jeering. If it can hide on this island.
Jack's been everywhere. Where could a beast live? Beast my foot. Perl muttered
something, and the assembly laughed again. Ralph leaned forward. What does
he say? Jack listened to Perl's answer and then let go of him. Percal,
released, surrounded by the comfortable presence of humans, fell in the long
grass and went to sleep. Jack cleared his throat, then reported casually, "He
says, "The beast comes out of the sea."
The last laugh died away. Ralph turned involuntarily, a black humped figure
against the lagoon. The assembly looked with him, considered the vast stretches
of water, the high sea beyond, unknown indigo of infinite possibility, heard
silently the s and whisper from the reef. Maurice spoke so loudly that they
jumped. Daddy said they haven't found all the animals in the sea yet. Argument
started again. Ralph held out the glimmering conchk and Maurice took it
obediently. The meeting subsided. I mean, when Jack says you can be
frightened because people are frightened anyway, that's all right. But when he
says there's only pigs on this island, I expect he's right. But he doesn't know.
Not really. Not certainly. I mean, Maurice took a breath. My daddy says there's
things. What do you call them that make ink? Squids that are hundreds of yards
long and eat whales whole. He paused again and laughed gay. I don't believe
in the beast, of course. As Piggy says, life's scientific. But we don't know, do
we? Not certainly, I mean, someone shouted. A squid couldn't come up out of
the water. Could, couldn't. In a moment, the platform was full of arguing, just
sticulating shadows. To Ralph, seated, this seemed the breaking up of sanity.
Fear, beasts, no general agreement that the fire was all important, and when one
tried to get the thing straight, the argument sheared off, bringing up fresh,
unpleasant matter. He could see a whiteness in the gloom near him, so he
grabbed it from Maurice and blew as loudly as he could. The assembly was
shocked into silence. Simon was close to him, laying hands on the conchk. Simon
felt a perilous necessity to speak, but to speak in an assembly was a terrible
thing to him. Maybe, he said hesitantly. Maybe there is a beast. The
assembly cried out savagely, and Ralph stood up in amazement. You, Simon, you
believe in this? I don't know, said Simon. His heartbeats were choking him.
But the storm broke. Sit down. Shut up.
Take the conchk. Saw you. Shut up, Ralph shouted. Hear him. He's got the conchk.
What I mean is maybe it's only us nuts. That was from Piggy shocked out
of decorum. Simon went on. We could be sort of Simon became inarticulate in his
effort to express mankind's essential illness. Inspiration came to him. What's
the dirtiest thing there is? As an answer, Jack dropped into the
uncomprehending silence that followed it the one crude expressive syllable.
Release was immense. Those little onins who had climbed back on the twister fell
off again and did not mind. The hunters were screaming with delight. Simon's
effort fell about him in ruins. The laughter beat him cruy and he shrank
away defenseless to his seat. At last the assembly was silent again. Someone
spoke out of turn. Maybe he means it's some sort of ghost. Ralph lifted the
conchk and peered into the gloom. The lightest thing was the pale beach.
Surely the little onlands were nearer.
Yes, there was no doubt about it. They were huddled into a tight knot of bodies
in the central grass. A flurry of wind made the palms talk, and the noise
seemed very loud now that darkness and silence made it so noticeable. Two gray
trunks rubbed each other with an evil speaking that no one had noticed by day.
Piggy took the conchk out of his hands.
His voice was indignant. I don't believe in no ghosts ever. Jack was up too,
unaccountably angry. Who cares what you believe, fatty? I got the conchk. There
was the sound of a brief tussle, and the conchk moved to and fro. You give me the
conchk back. Ralph pushed between them and got a thump on the chest. He
wrestled the conchk from someone and sat down breathlessly. There's too much talk
about ghosts. We ought to have left all this for daylight. A hushed and
anonymous voice broke in. Perhaps that's what the beast is, a ghost. The assembly
was shaken as by a wind. There's too much talking out of turn, Ralph said.
Because we can't have proper assemblies if you don't stick to the rules. He
stopped again. The careful plan of this assembly had broken down. What do you
want me to say then? I was wrong to call this assembly so late. We'll have a vote
on them on ghosts, I mean, and then go to the shelters because we're all tired.
No, Jack is itit. Wait a minute. I'll say here and now that I don't believe in
ghosts. Or I don't think I do, but I don't like the thought of them. Not now,
that is in the dark. But we were going to decide what's what. He raised the
conchk for a moment. Very well then. I suppose what's what is whether there are
ghosts or not. He thought for a moment, formulating the question. Who thinks
there may be ghosts? For a long time there was silence and no apparent
movement. Then Ralph peered into the gloom and made out the hands. He spoke
flatly. I see the world, that understandable and lawful world, was
slipping away. Once there was this and that, and now, and the ship had gone.
The conchk was snatched from his hands, and Piggy's voice trilled. I didn't vote
for no ghosts. He whirled round on the assembly. Remember that all of you? They
heard him stamp. What are we, humans or animals or savages? What's grown-ups
going to think? Going off hunting pigs, letting fires out. And now, a shadow
fronted him tempestuously. You shut up, you fat slug. There was a moment
struggle and the glimmering conchk jigged up and down. Ralph leapt to his
feet. Jack. Jack, you haven't got the conchk. Let him speak. Jack's face swam
near him. And you shut up. Who are you anyway? Sitting there telling people
what to do. You can't hunt. You can't sing. I'm chief. I was chosen. Why
should choosing make any difference?
Just giving orders that don't make any sense. Piggy's got the conchk. That's
right. Favor Piggy as you always do.
Jack. Jack's voice shouted shouted in bitter mimickry. "Jack, Jack, the
rules," shouted Ralph. "You're breaking the rules. Who cares?" Ralph summoned
his wits. "Because the rules are the only thing we've got." But Jack was
shouting against him. Bollocks to the rules. "We're strong. We hunt. If
there's a beast, we'll hunt it down.
We'll close in and beat and beat and beat." He gave a wild whoop and leapt
down to the pale sand. At once the platform was full of noise and
excitement, scramblings, screams, and laughter. The assembly shredded away and
became a discursive and random scatter from the palms to the water and away
along the beach beyond nights sight.
Ralph found his cheek touching the conchk and took it from Piggy. What's
grown-ups going to say? Cried Piggy again. Look at him. The sound of mock
hunting, hysterical laughter, and real terror came from the beach. Blow the
conchk, Ralph. Piggy was so close that Ralph could see the glint of his one
glass. There's the fire. Can't they see?
You got to be tough now. Make them do what you want. Ralph answered in the
cautious voice of one who rehearses a theorem. If I blow the conchk and they
don't come back, then we've had it. We shan keep the fire going. We'll be like
animals. We'll never be rescued. If you don't blow, we'llll soon be animals
anyway. I can't see what they're doing, but I can hear. The dispersed figures
had come together on the sand and were a dense black mass that revolved. They
were chanting something, and little onins that had had enough were
staggering away. Howling, Ralph raised the conchk to his lips and then lowered
it. The trouble is. Are there ghosts, Piggy? Or beasts? Of course there
aren't. Why not? Cuz things wouldn't make sense. Houses and streets and TV,
they wouldn't work. The dancing, chanting boys had worked themselves away
till their sound was nothing but a wordless rhythm. But suppose they don't
make sense. Not here on this island.
Supposing things are watching us and waiting. Ralph shuddered violently and
moved closer to Piggy so that they bumped frighteningly. You stop talking
like that. We got enough trouble, Ralph.
And I've had as much as I can stand. If there is ghosts, I ought to give up
being chief. Hear him. Oh lord. Oh no.
Piggy gripped Ralph's arm. If Jack was chief, he'd have all hunting and no
fire. We'd be here till we died. His voice ran up to a squeak. Who's that
sitting there? Me, Simon. Fat lot of good we are, said Ralph. Three blind
mice. I'll give up. If you give up, said Piggy in an appalled whisper. What had
happened to me? Nothing. He hates me. I don't know why. If he could do what he
wanted. You're all right. He respects you. Besides, you'd hit him. You were
having a nice fight with him just now. I had the conchk, said Piggy simply. I had
a right to speak. Simon stirred in the dark. Go on, being chief. You shut up,
young Simon. Why couldn't you say there wasn't a beast? I'm scared of him, said
Piggy. And that's why I know him. If you're scared of someone, you hate him,
but you can't stop thinking about him.
You kid yourself he's all right, really.
And then when you see him again, it's like asthma and you can't breathe. I
tell you what, he hates you too, Ralph.
Me? Why me? I don't know. You got him over the fire. And you're chief and he
isn't. But he's he's Jack Meridu. I've been in bed so much I've done some
thinking. I know about people. I know about me and him. He can't hurt you, but
if you stand out of the way, he'd hurt the next thing, and that's me. Piggy's
right, Ralph. There's you and Jack. Go on being chief. We're all drifting and
things are going rotten. At home, there was always a grown-up. Please, sir.
Please, miss. And then you got an answer. How I wish. I wish my auntie was
here. I wish my father. Oh, what's the use? Keep the fire going. The dance was
over, and the hunters were going back to the shelters. Grown-ups know things,
said Piggy. They ain't afraid of the dark. They'd meet and have tea and
discuss. Then things would be all right.
They wouldn't set fire to the island or lose. They'd build a ship. The three
boys stood in the darkness, striving unsuccessfully to convey the majesty of
adult life. They wouldn't quarrel or break my specs or talk about a beast. If
only they could get a message to us, cried Ralph desperately. If only they
could send us something grownup, a sign or something. A thin whale out of the
darkness chilled them and set them grabbing for each other. Then the whale
rose, remote and unearly, and turned to an inarticulate gibbering. Per Weis
Madison of the vicorage, Harkert St.
Anthony, lying in the long grass, was living through circumstances in which
the incantation of his address was powerless to help him. Lord of the Flies. Chapter 6. Beast